abcya.com 2018-12-07

# ABCya! Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

Updated and effective as of August 21, 2018. 

ABCya.com is a teacher-created website brought to you by ABCya.com LLC ("ABCya") that provides fun and educational games for kids to use under the guidance of their parents and teachers. In this policy, we refer to our visitors younger than age 13 as "Children." We provide this privacy policy to inform parents and other users about our privacy practices for ABCya.com, our ABCYa Games mobile app, and any other ABCya online service that links to this Privacy Policy (the "Platform"), as required by the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA"). Note that this Privacy Policy does not cover information collected offline or through ABCya mobile apps that post a separate privacy policy. 

Please review our full privacy policy below - but here are some key points to know: 

\- The Platform does not require Children to provide their name, address, or other contact information in order to play games. We, and third-party service providers, may automatically collect IP address and similar device identifiers from Platform visitors - but only for analytical and other internal-operations purposes. 

\- The Platform does collect personal information from parents, teachers, and other adults (for example, if you subscribe to a paid account). 

\- Unless you purchase an ad-free subscription, we have advertisements on the Platform, which are served by third-party companies. However, these ads are not targeted to a specific user. (We use only contextual advertising methods and not interest-based advertising methods). 

In addition to this privacy policy, please review our [Terms of Use](http://www.abcya.com/abcya_terms_of_use.htm), which govern your use of the Platform, and our [Payment Terms,](http://www.abcya.com/payment_terms.htm) which contain additional terms applicable to paid subscriptions. 

This Privacy Policy explains:

  * _WHAT INFORMATION DOES ABCYA COLLECT AND HOW DO WE USE IT?_

  * _DOES THE PLATFORM USE COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES?_

  * _HOW DOES ABCYA SHARE COLLECTED INFORMATION?_

  * _DOES THE PLATFORM USE THIRD-PARTY ANALYTICS PROVIDERS AND AD SERVERS?_

  * _ARE THERE THIRD-PARTY LINKS ON THE PLATFORM?_

  * _WHAT RIGHTS DO PARENTS HAVE?_

  * _WILL MY INFORMATION TRANSFER TO THE UNITED STATES?_

  * _WHAT STEPS DOES ABCYA TAKE TO SECURE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?_

  * _HOW WILL YOU NOTIFY ME IF THIS PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES?_

  * _HOW DO I CONTACT ABCYA?_

### WHAT INFORMATION DOES ABCYA COLLECT AND HOW DO WE USE IT?

ABCya collects "Personal Information" which is information that could reasonably be used to contact you or to identify you as specific person (for example, first and last name, mailing address, email address, or telephone number), and other information, some of which we collect automatically when you visit the Platform. 

_Personal Information_

The Platform does not generally collect name, address, or other contact information from Children, other than the limited circumstances set forth below. However, we, and our third-party service providers, may collect a "Device Identifier" associated with the computer, mobile phone or other device used to access the Platform (for example, an IP address). These Device Identifiers are considered Personal Information for Children. We, and our third-party service providers, use Device Identifier information solely to support internal operations, including operating Platform features and serving contextual ads. 

The Platform may occasionally collect a Child's first name and online contact information (typically, an e-mail address) solely for the following purposes: 

\- For one-time use of that information. For example, we may answer a question submitted through the Platform or allow a sweepstakes entry. Once we have responded or contacted the Child one time, we delete the online contact information and will not use it to re-contact the Child; 

\- OR 

\- For the sole purpose of: protecting the security or integrity of the Platform; taking precautions against liability; responding to judicial process; or providing information to law enforcement agencies or for an investigation on a matter related to public safety. 

Additionally, in some instances a game may request that a user provide a name (e.g., to identify a particular player in a multi-player game). In those instances, the name provided is only stored locally on the user's device and not collected by us. 

Please note that we will not condition a Child's participation in a Platform activity on the Child's disclosing more than is reasonably necessary to participate in such activity. We use Personal Information only for the purpose that it was provided and for internal purposes. 

In some cases, we will collect Personal Information from a parent, teacher, or other adult. We use information collected from adults: 

\- to process transactions and provide our products and services; 

\- to provide information, products, or services that we believe will interest you or you have agreed to receive, including special offers from us and other companies; 

\- to contact you regarding your account, our policies or your use of the Platform; 

\- to improve our products and services and for our internal business purposes; and 

\- for other purposes disclosed at the time you provide your information, with your consent, and as described in this Privacy Policy. 

_Other Information_

When you use the Platform, we (and our third-party service providers) may automatically or passively collect certain "Usage Information," such as the browser and operating system you are using, information on how you arrived at the Platform, and all of the areas within our Platform that you visit. We may use Usage Information for a variety of purposes, including enhancing or otherwise improving the Platform and our products and services. 

### DOES THE PLATFORM USE COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES?

We, and our third-party service providers, may use the following or similar technologies to collect Usage Information and Device Identifier: 

_Cookies & Local Storage._ A cookie is a data file placed on your computer or other device when you visit the Platform. Certain web browsers and add-ons we utilize, such as Adobe Flash, may provide additional local data storage mechanisms that are used in a manner similar to cookies. For example, a Flash cookie is a data file placed on your device via the Adobe Flash plugin, which may be built-in to or downloaded by you to your computer or other device. Cookies, Flash cookies, and other local storage may be used for various purposes, such as supporting game play, enabling Platform features, and similar operational purposes. If you choose to disable cookies or to adjust privacy settings on your device, some features of the Platform may not function properly. For more information about Flash and the privacy choices Adobe offers, visit [ Adobe](http://www.adobe.com/privacy/flash-player.html). 

_Web Beacons._ We and our third-party service providers may use web beacons (small graphic images or other web programming code, also known as "1x1 GIFs" or "clear GIFs") and similar technologies. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including counting visitors and monitoring how users navigate the Platform. 

_Embedded Scripts._ An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the Platform, such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your device, is active only while you are connected to the Platform, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter. 

### HOW DOES ABCYA SHARE COLLECTED INFORMATION?

_Children_

ABCya does not disclose Children's Personal Information to third parties, except with regard to the safety and security of the Platform as discussed above, and to service providers who provide support for the internal operations of the Platform and who do not disclose or use the Personal Information for any other purpose. These service providers provide support services, such as hosting the Platform and operating its features, or performing other administrative services. ABCya may provide these companies with access to Children's Personal Information so that they can perform services on our behalf. These service providers have agreed to keep Personal Information they obtain from ABCya confidential and secure. 

_Adults_

With regard to Parents, teachers, or other adults who have provided information in connection with a paid subscription, we may disclose such information (including Personal Information) with your consent, as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, and in the following limited circumstances: 

_\- Other Third Party Service Providers._ In addition to those third-party service providers described above, we may provide information collected from adult users of the Platform to other service providers so that they can perform services on our behalf, such as processing transactions, addressing customer service inquiries, and sending email or other communications. In some instances, you may provide your Personal Information directly to an identified third party through a widget or other third party-hosted feature on the Platform, such as when providing payment information during the subscription process. 

_\- Administrative or Legal Reasons._ We may also disclose information to third parties: (i) where, in our opinion, such disclosure is required by law (including to respond to a subpoena); (ii) at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; or (iii) to protect and/or defend policies applicable to the Platform or to protect ourselves or any other individual or entity. 

_\- Business Transfers._ We may also disclose information, including Personal Information: (i) to a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of the Platform or (ii) in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, bankruptcy, the sale of any ABCya ownership interest or asset, or other corporate change, including, during the course of any due diligence process.

### DOES THE PLATFORM USE THIRD-PARTY ANALYTICS PROVIDERS AND AD SERVERS? 

ABCya works with advertising companies, analytics providers, and other service providers to serve advertisements on the Platform, to provide us with information regarding Platform traffic, and to serve our advertisements elsewhere online. Our service providers may set and access their own tracking technologies on your device. They may collect or we may give them access to your Device Identifier and Usage Information, provided that your Device Identifier will be used only to support internal operations. We only allow contextual advertising on our Platform. (You will not see ads targeted to you as a specific user).

###  ARE THERE THIRD-PARTY LINKS ON THE PLATFORM? 

Certain content on the Platform may be hosted and served by third parties. In addition, the Platform may contain links to third-party web sites that we do not control. We are not responsible for the privacy or data collection practices of any third party. 

### WHAT RIGHTS DO PARENTS HAVE?

Parents have the right to review and request that ABCya delete any Personal Information that the Platform has collected and retained about their Child. If you would like to request that ABCya delete any Personal Information we may have about your Child (such as first name and contact information prior to the Platform's one-time use) or if you would like to request that the Platform make no further collection of Personal Information from your Child, please contact ABCya at support (at) abcya (dot) com. 

### WILL MY INFORMATION TRANSFER TO THE UNITED STATES? 

If you do not live in the United States, know that information we collect will be transferred to and processed in the United States. By using the Platform, you consent to the collection, transfer, processing and storage of your information in the United States, a jurisdiction in which the privacy laws may not be as comprehensive as those in the country where you reside and/or are a citizen.

### WHAT STEPS DOES ABCYA TAKE TO SECURE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?

ABCya takes reasonable steps to protect the confidentiality and security of Personal Information collected from Platform users. We also take reasonable steps to release Children's Personal Information, if any, only to service providers and third parties who are capable of and have agreed to maintain the confidentiality and security of that information. 

### HOW WILL YOU NOTIFY ME IF THIS PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES?

ABCya may update this Privacy Policy at any time and any changes will be effective upon posting (unless otherwise specified). We will provide notice on the Platform and we may also provide notice in other ways, such as sending you an email. Your continued use of the Platform after the effective date of the revised Privacy Policy (or such other act as specified in the revised Privacy Policy) will constitute your consent. However, we will obtain consent (opt-in or opt-out for adults and prior parental consent for Children) before using or disclosing Personal Information in a manner materially different from the Privacy Policy posted at the time of collection and any prior parental consent received.

### HOW DO I CONTACT ABCYA?

ABCya.com LLC is the operator of this Platform and questions regarding this Privacy Policy and use of Personal Information should be directed to ABCya.com through any of the following methods: 

Mailing address: ABCya.com LLC  
11 South Angel Street #333  
Providence, Rhode Island 02906 

Email: support (at) abcya (dot) com 

Call toll-free (855) 250-9249 

### INFORMATION FOR RESIDENTS OF THE EUROPEAN UNION AND THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA

This section of the Privacy Policy applies only if you use our Sites or Apps, on iTunes, Google Play, Amazon and Microsoft, covered by the Privacy Policy from a country in the European Union or another member state of the European Economic Area (“EEA”), and it supplements the information in the Privacy Policy.

ABCya.com, L.L.C. is the data controller for processing of information defined as personal data under applicable data protection law (“Personal Data”).

### LEGAL BASIS FOR DATA PROCESSING

We process Personal Data for the purposes set out in the Privacy Policy. Our legal bases to process Personal Data include processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract between us, in the case of subscription users (for example, to provide you with services you request and to identify and authenticate you so you may use the website); necessary to comply with legal requirements and applicable accounting standards and to make mandatory disclosures to law enforcement and regulatory authorities; necessary for our legitimate interests (for example, to manage our relationship with you, to improve the website and our services, to protect our property and safeguard against fraud and malware, to make or defend legal claims); and based on consent by our customers (for example, to communicate with you about our products and services and provide you with marketing information). Where we process your Personal Data with your consent, you may subsequently withdraw consent at any time by contacting us (using the contact instructions below), without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.

### EU DATA SUBJECT RIGHTS

The EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and other applicable data protection laws provide certain rights for individual data subjects (“EU Data Subject Rights”). You may decline to share certain Personal Data with us, in which case we may not be able to provide some of the features and functionality of our services. These rights include, in accordance with applicable law, the rights to access or rectify Personal Data, object to or restrict further processing, or request the erasure of Personal Data or, where feasible, to have it moved to a new service provider (“data portability”). You must be 16 years or older to make a request or else have your parent contact us on your behalf.

Normally, we can respond to requests for access within 48 hours. If we cannot honor your request concerning Data Subject Rights within 30 days, we will inform you and provide an explanation. When technically feasible, at your request, we will provide your Personal Data to you or transmit it directly to another controller.

We retain your Personal Data while you have an account with us and while you are using our services or continuing to visit our Site. We will retain your Personal Data for as long as it is reasonably necessary for the purposes set out in the Privacy Policy, considering the time period reasonably necessary to: provide the services to you; exercise the choices and rights you have requested; comply with our contractual obligations; enforce our terms for use of the services; and comply with legal and regulatory requirements.

If you have any unresolved privacy concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily after contacting us, you have the right to contact the relevant national data protection supervisory authority and lodge a complaint.

### CHILDREN

Our Privacy Policy addresses the information we collect from children, how we use it and parental access. Note that we do not knowingly sell goods or services to children younger than age 16.

### CONTACT US

For all EU Data Subject Rights requests, please contact us at support@abcya.com. You must put the statement "Your EU Data Subject Rights" in the subject field of your request and include in the request the name of the Services with respect to which you are requesting the information, as well as your contact information.
